Solution-driven Back-end developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumerfocused websites using HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over a year, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Work History

2021-01 - System Integrator and Full-stack 2022-04 Developer

Francistown Digital City (FDC) In Botswana Accountancy College, Francistown

- Defined and maintained databases to deliver responsiveness to data client requests.
- Implemented robust security and data protection measures.
- Built flexible, reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Developed web platform back ends using NodeJS and Flask frameworks.
- Wrote unit tests to evaluate high code coverage.
- Troubleshoot and debug applications and learn about new technologies.
- Worked in Agile Scrum team environment with high-tempo production cadence.
- Authored code in Python and JavaScript within Django framework.
- Managed efficient SQL queries and data transport.
- Led the development team in creating digital systems for clients by using Java Server Pages, HTML 5 and jQuery technologies.
- Develop functional and sustainable web applications with clean codes.

Education

Bachelor of Science: COMPUTER SYSTEM ENGINEERING

Chandida Matiha

Contact

Address

Francistown P O Box 20913

Phone

76366265

E-mail

<u>chandidamth0@gmail.com</u>

Skills

Building systems and services

System and program efficiency

Problem-Solving

Database Management

Vue.js and Node.js

OOP

GIT

Django

Languages

Java

Python

Dart

HTML and CSS

JavaScript

PHP

SQL

2018-07 -2022-07

Certifications

2021-09 Cybersecurity - Edureka

2020-02 Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) - Cisco

Networking Academy

Accomplishments

NATIONAL SCIENCE WEEK & STEM FESTIVAL HACKATHON/ BOTSWANA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY

 Mobile app development, as a result, scooping first place in the Biust 2020 National Science Week and STEM festival.

Additional Information

Mr. Rebaone Mlalazi

School of Computing and Information Systems Botswana Accountancy College

Francistown

+267 74346524

Mr. Bakang Hiri

School of Computing and Information Systems Botswana Accountancy College

Francistown

+267 76097031